<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<rss version="0.92" xml:lang="en-US">
	<channel>
		<title>MMO-Champion - World of Warcraft Guides and Raid Strategies - News</title>
		<link>http://www.mmo-champion.com/index.php</link>
		<description><![CDATA[Live information from MMO-Champion - World of Warcraft Guides and Raid Strategies]]></description>
		<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Icecrown Citadel Videos, Blue posts]]></title>
			<link>http://www.mmo-champion.com/news-2/icecrown-citadel-videos-blue-posts/</link>
			<description>
<![CDATA[<font size="3" style="line-height: 1.3em;"><b>PTR Raid Testing Videos</b></font><br />A few guilds released videos of their raid testing on PTRs during the past two days. A video of Sindragosa tested a few hours ago is also included. <br /><br /><div align="center"><object width="640" height="405"><param name="movie" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/buCo8JSXzLM"><b>BlizzCast #11: BlizzCon 2009 in Review</b></font><br /><div class="blizzquotewrap"><div class="blizzquoteinner"><span class="corners-top"><span></span></span><div class="blizzquoteheader"><span>Quote from: <b>Zarhym (<a href="http://blue.mmo-champion.com/1/20677332669-blizzcast-11-blizzcon-2009-in-review.html" target="_blank" style="color: white;">Source</a>)</span></b></div><div class="blizzquote">In our eleventh episode of BlizzCast, we have a roundtable discussion with members of the community team to recap the major happenings, announcements, and other highlights of this year’s BlizzCon. Join our discussion as we relive some of our favorite moments from the show.<br /><br /><a href="http://us.blizzard.com/en-us/community/blizzcast/archive/episode11.html?rhtml=y" target="_blank">http://us.blizzard.com/en-us/community/blizzcast/archive/episode11.html?rhtml=y</a></div><span class="corners-bottom"><span></span></span></div></div><br /><br /><font size="3" style="line-height: 1.3em;"><b>Blue posts</b></font><br /><div class="blizzquotewrap"><div class="blizzquoteinner"><span class="corners-top"><span></span></span><div class="blizzquoteheader"><span>Quote from <b>Blizzard staff</b></span></div><div class="blizzquote"><span style="color: white;"><b>New LFG Channel</b></span><br />&nbsp;I don&#39;t think a world-wide LFG channel would be something you&#39;d really want. It would immediately become the global chat channel for trade, spam and Chuck Norris jokes.<br /><br />On live it&#39;s restricted to people using the LFG tool. The new dungeon tool honestly makes matches so quickly under most conditions that that implementation won&#39;t work. We feared people would just use the /trade channel if we didn&#39;t make a similar /lfg channel. (<a href="http://blue.mmo-champion.com/13/20677352474-dont-restrict-lfg-channel-to-cities.html" target="_blank"><b><span style="color: white;">Source</span></b></a>)<br /><br /><span style="color: white;"><b>Dungeon system gear requirements</b></span><br />It uses all the items you own to make that determination, not just what you have equipped.<br /><br />Honestly though, we are really relaxed about how we use this restriction. It&#39;s basically in there to prevent newly minted 80s in quest greens from rolling into a heroic dungeon that is likely to kick their butt. Most players sophisticated enough to be on these boards won&#39;t run into it in day to day practice. (<a href="http://blue.mmo-champion.com/13/20677672386-lfg-tool-and-dual-spec.html" target="_blank"><b><span style="color: white;">Source</span></b></a>)<br /><br /><span style="color: white;"><b>Looking for raid NOT working cross-realms</b></span><br />If a dungeon group falls apart after 1-2 bosses, it&#39;s not nearly as big of a deal as if a raid group falls apart after 5 bosses of Ulduar. If the group wants to continue it and somebody from another realm (who can&#39;t really contact you easily) beat you to it and cleared it with their friends, that would probably leave you a bit upset. This is just one example that came to me off the top of my head.<br /><br />Sure, there could be ways to resolve this with a variety of rules, but we will see how things go for now. A lot of raids are able to happen once people are found so we mainly just want to make it easier to find people for now. (<a href="http://blue.mmo-champion.com/1/20677232147-say-no-to-looking-for-raid.html" target="_blank"><b><span style="color: white;">Source</span></b></a>)<br /><br /><span style="color: white;"><b>Additional stats in monsters tooltips for Cataclysm</b></span><br />We&#39;d be more likely to just put it on the stats screen as a tooltip for your hit chance for example. To get the information from particular creatures will require a little more work on our part. (<a href="http://blue.mmo-champion.com/26/20677632379-icewell-radiance-is-in.html" target="_blank"><b><span style="color: white;">Source</span></b></a>)<br /><br /><span style="color: white;"><b>Boss difficulty</b></span><br />I&#39;m talking about an Icecrown boss being tougher than an Ulduar boss, not that the Ulduar bosses look at how much gear you have and scale themselves up accordingly.<br /><br />Bosses get more damage and health. If they also got more expertise, defense and maybe armor then as character item level grew their relative strength to boss stats would not increase. As it is they increase enormously, requiring the bosses to have even more health and even more damage. Shifting some of that health and damage to other stats would fix a lot of problems. (<a href="http://blue.mmo-champion.com/26/20677632379-icewell-radiance-is-in.html" target="_blank"><b><span style="color: white;">Source</span></b></a>)<br /><br /><span style="color: white;"><b>Giving wands to level 1 characters</b></span><br />As far as wands go, we definitely do not want to give them to casters at level 1. Wands play a very different role for casters than melee weapons do for melee classes. They&#39;re generally used as mana conservation DPS. We are removing the Attack button from level 1 casters&#39; action bars specifically so new players aren&#39;t inclined to walk around trying to melee foes without learning the way the spells available to them function. Giving them a wand and placing the Shoot icon on the action bar would lead to the same issue for players new to the game rolling casters. They might be inclined to run around using their wands rather than learning their class spells.<br /><br />With mana regeneration being greatly improved for the level 1-10 experience in patch 3.3, mana issues should not warrant the use of wands too often when players are getting started. Because of this, we want to make sure new players are focused purely on learning how to use spells to kill enemy targets. (<a href="http://blue.mmo-champion.com/1/20677352112-why-give-rogues-dw-at-level-1.html" target="_blank"><b><span style="color: white;">Source</span></b></a>)<br /><br /><font size="3" style="line-height: 1.3em;"><b><span style="color: #90FF53;">Chill of the Throne / Tanking</span></b></font> (See <a href="http://www.mmo-champion.com/news-2/chill-of-the-throne-tanking-and-you!/" target="_blank"><b><span style="color: orange;">Chill of the Throne, Tanking, and You!</span></b></a>)<br /><span style="color: white;"><b>Reasons behind the change</b></span><br />I&#39;ll address this one more time and then leave it because I think players are more interested in trying to turn this into a huge tanking nerf than understand what&#39;s going on.<br /><br />We would not have this problem if Icecrown gear had been item level 245 or so, as we originally intended. We added a few extra tiers of gear to support heroic modes. We felt like we had to do that to have different difficulty levels and make raiding more accessible overall. We felt like we had to reward the harder modes with the better gear or nobody would have been very interested.<br /><br />The proportions of relative stats on your gear are not the problem. They are proportional, give or take a little, at every tier except for stats like hit that cap out. The problem is not the class and item teams being out of sync. In fact, they are the same team. (<a href="http://blue.mmo-champion.com/26/20677632379-icewell-radiance-is-in.html" target="_blank"><b><span style="color: white;">Source</span></b></a>)<br /><br /><span style="color: white;"><b>Diminishing returns</b></span><br />The 20% nerf is applied after diminishing returns. That is why I am saying it won&#39;t affect the relative value of dodge and parry. The Icewell Radiance won&#39;t get you closer to diminishing returns by itself.<br /><br />The whole point of this change is so bosses can hit less hard but more often, for the same damage over time but with fewer deadly spikes. That should feel better to everyone overall. The reason I am reluctant to say that is because some players are going to go into Icecrown, find it hard, and then expect us to buff their class.<br /><br />It won&#39;t be Brutallus hard, at least most of the bosses and at least on normal mode. We&#39;re not going to be particularly sympathetic to players who find heroic mode too hard. (<a href="http://blue.mmo-champion.com/26/20677632379-icewell-radiance-is-in.html" target="_blank"><b><span style="color: white;">Source</span></b></a>)<br /><br /><span style="color: white;"><b>Stamina less important?</b></span><br />It arguably makes stam less important (though it will always be important for tanks). Many players are probably telling you right now that only stamina and armor are important because if you ever fail to avoid two boss hits in a row that you&#39;re going to die. Under that environment, avoidance loses a lot of value.<br /><br />If bosses hit for less in IC (which they will, since they will hit more often) then the value of avoidance for purposes of survival increases.<br /><br />I still expect many tanks will die in two hits until they get geared up a little. But they will, and then the ability to survive two hits in a row won&#39;t be as big an issue. (<a href="http://blue.mmo-champion.com/26/20677632379-icewell-radiance-is-in.html" target="_blank"><b><span style="color: white;">Source</span></b></a>)<br /><br /><span style="color: white;"><b>Effective Health</b></span><br />I am going to attempt to explain the disconnect the community and the developers have over effective health.<br /><br />When I first learned to tank, long before I came to Blizzard, I learned that effective health is a measurement of your stamina in relationship to your armor. This is a pretty easy number to generate. It&#39;s reasonable to include say shield block and other simple forms of mitigation into the calculation.<br /><br />However, you cannot directly translate effective health into best tank. Avoidance matters. If it didn&#39;t, we would have no reason to nerf it in Icecrown. Good tanks don&#39;t depend too much on avoidance, but great tanks understand its value.<br /><br />Fur...</div><span class="corners-bottom"><span></span></span></div></div>]]>
			</description>
			<comments>http://www.mmo-champion.com/news-2/icecrown-citadel-videos-blue-posts/?action=post</comments>
			<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
			<pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2009 06:08:03 GMT</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.mmo-champion.com/news-2/icecrown-citadel-videos-blue-posts/msg1673439/#msg1673439</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Sindragosa US PTR Testing]]></title>
			<link>http://www.mmo-champion.com/news-2/sindragosa-us-ptr-testing/</link>
			<description>
<![CDATA[<b><span style="color: red;">Update</span></b> - Added abilities! (Yup, already)<br /><br /><font size="3" style="line-height: 1.3em;"><b>Sindragosa US PTR Testing</b></font><br />US Players will get a chance to fight Sindragosa, the Queen of the Frostbrood on US PTRs tonight! Stay tuned for streams, abilities, and more!<br /><br /><div align="center"><img src="http://static.mmo-champion.com/mmoc/images/news/2009/october/sindragosas.jpg" alt="" border="0" /></div><br /><div align="center"><font size="3" style="line-height: 1.3em;"><b>Streams</b></font></div><br /><div align="center">Testing is now finished.</div><br /><div align="center"><font size="3" style="line-height: 1.3em;"><b>Abilities</b></font></div><br /><table bgcolor="#FFFFFF" width="700px" border="0" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="1" style="border-left: 1px solid #96BC27; border-right: 1px solid #96BC27; border-top: 1px solid #96BC27; margin:auto;">
			<tr><td style="padding-left: 5px"><b>Sindragosa</b></td></tr>
			</table>
			<table bgcolor="#FFFFFF" width="700px" class="sortable" border="0" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="1" style="border: 1px solid #96BC27; margin:auto;">
			<tr bgcolor="#96BC27">
			<td width="30">&nbsp;</td>
			<td width="150"><b>Spell</b></td>
			<td width="520"><b>Description</b></td>
			</tr>
			</table>
			<table bgcolor="#FFFFFF" width="700px" class="sortable" border="0" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="1" style="border: 1px solid #96BC27; margin:auto;">
<tr class="vloot2">
	<td><img width="30" height="30" src="http://db.mmo-champion.com/static/img/icons/spell_frost_frostshock.png"></td>
	<td><a target="_blank" href="http://db.mmo-champion.com/s/71050/frost-aura/" style="font-weight:bold;">Frost Aura</a></td>
	<td style="font-weight: bold;">Deals 4500 Frost damage to all nearby enemies every 3.0 sec. &#32;Instant</td>
</tr>
<tr class="vloot2">
	<td><img width="30" height="30" src="http://db.mmo-champion.com/static/img/icons/spell_arcane_focusedpower.png"></td>
	<td><a target="_blank" href="http://db.mmo-champion.com/s/69762/unchained-magic/" style="font-weight:bold;">Unchained Magic</a></td>
	<td style="font-weight: bold;">Inflicts an arcane malediction on the target, causing any spells cast to result in a backlash of Arcane power after 8 sec. &#32;Multiple spellcasts by the afflicted target will intensify the backlash. Unlimited range. Instant</td>
</tr>
<tr class="vloot2">
	<td><img width="30" height="30" src="http://db.mmo-champion.com/static/img/icons/spell_arcane_arcanetorrent.png"></td>
	<td><a target="_blank" href="http://db.mmo-champion.com/s/69766/instability/" style="font-weight:bold;">Instability</a></td>
	<td style="font-weight: bold;">Using magic while afflicted with Unchained Magic will build up unstable energy, dealing 2000 Arcane damage to the caster per spell cast, 8 sec after spellcasting ends.<br/> Instant</td>
</tr>
<tr class="vloot2">
	<td><img width="30" height="30" src="http://db.mmo-champion.com/static/img/icons/ability_warrior_cleave.png"></td>
	<td><a target="_blank" href="http://db.mmo-champion.com/s/19983/cleave/" style="font-weight:bold;">Cleave</a></td>
	<td style="font-weight: bold;">Inflicts normal damage plus 50 to an enemy and its nearest allies, affecting up to 10 targets. Melee range. Instant</td>
</tr>
<tr class="vloot2">
	<td><img width="30" height="30" src="http://db.mmo-champion.com/static/img/icons/spell_frost_coldhearted.png"></td>
	<td><a target="_blank" href="http://db.mmo-champion.com/s/70109/permeating-chill/" style="font-weight:bold;">Permeating Chill</a></td>
	<td style="font-weight: bold;">Causes those who attack Sindragosa with physical attacks to be chilled to the bone, reducing their movement speed by 1000% per application, for 8 sec seconds. &#32;Instant</td>
</tr>
<tr class="vloot2">
	<td><img width="30" height="30" src="http://db.mmo-champion.com/static/img/icons/spell_frost_frostnova.png"></td>
	<td><a target="_blank" href="http://db.mmo-champion.com/s/71056/frost-breath/" style="font-weight:bold;">Frost Breath</a></td>
	<td style="font-weight: bold;">Inflicts 37000 to 43000 Frost damage to enemies in a 60 yard cone in front of the caster. In addition, the targets' attack speed and chance to dodge are decreased by 50% for 6 sec. Melee range. 1.5 sec cast</td>
</tr>
<tr class="vloot2">
	<td><img width="30" height="30" src="http://db.mmo-champion.com/static/img/icons/spell_frost_frozencore.png"></td>
	<td><a target="_blank" href="http://db.mmo-champion.com/s/70157/ice-tomb/" style="font-weight:bold;">Ice Tomb</a></td>
	<td style="font-weight: bold;">Conjures spheres of icy energy to entomb enemies in blocks of ice. Entombs the targeted foe and all enemies within 10 yards in ice, Ice Tombs have 786k HP in 25-Man Normal Mode. 200 yd range. Instant.</td>
</tr>
<tr class="vloot2">
	<td><img width="30" height="30" src="http://db.mmo-champion.com/static/img/icons/ability_hunter_markedfordeath.png"></td>
	<td><a target="_blank" href="http://db.mmo-champion.com/s/70126/frost-beacon/" style="font-weight:bold;">Frost Beacon</a></td>
	<td style="font-weight: bold;">Marks a target for imprisonment in an Ice Tomb. 200 yd range. Instant</td>
</tr>
<tr class="vloot2">
	<td><img width="30" height="30" src="http://db.mmo-champion.com/static/img/icons/spell_frost_iceshard.png"></td>
	<td><a target="_blank" href="http://db.mmo-champion.com/s/69846/frost-bomb/" style="font-weight:bold;">Frost Bomb</a></td>
	<td style="font-weight: bold;">Fires a missile towards a random target. When this missile lands, it deals 5655 to 6345 Shadow damage to all enemies within 10 yards of that location. Unlimited range. 1 sec cast</td>
</tr>
<tr class="vloot2">
	<td><img width="30" height="30" src="http://db.mmo-champion.com/static/img/icons/inv_misc_bone_03.png"></td>
	<td><a target="_blank" href="http://db.mmo-champion.com/s/71077/tail-smash/" style="font-weight:bold;">Tail Smash</a></td>
	<td style="font-weight: bold;">Inflicts 11250 to 18750 damage on enemies in a cone behind the caster, knocking them back. 45 yd range. 1 sec cast</td>
</tr>
<tr class="vloot2">
	<td><img width="30" height="30" src="http://db.mmo-champion.com/static/img/icons/spell_frost_icefloes.png"></td>
	<td><a target="_blank" href="http://db.mmo-champion.com/s/71047/blistering-cold/" style="font-weight:bold;">Blistering Cold</a></td>
	<td style="font-weight: bold;">Deals 35000 Frost damage to enemies within 25 yards. &#32;5 sec cast</td>
</tr>
<tr class="vloot2">
	<td><img width="30" height="30" src="http://db.mmo-champion.com/static/img/icons/spell_frost_arcticwinds.png"></td>
	<td><a target="_blank" href="http://db.mmo-champion.com/s/70117/icy-grip/" style="font-weight:bold;">Icy Grip</a></td>
	<td style="font-weight: bold;">Extend tendrils of frigid wind to pull all nearby enemies to the caster. 30 yd range. Instant</td>
</tr>


			</table><br /><div align="center"><font size="3" style="line-height: 1.3em;"><b>Achievements</b></font></div><br /><table bgcolor="#FFFFFF" border="0" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="1" style="border: 1px solid #96BC27; margin:auto;">
			<tr bgcolor="#96BC27">
			<td class="tableHeader" width="45"></td>
			<td class="tableHeader" width="655"><b>Description</b></td>
			</tr>
<tr bgcolor=""><td><img src="http://static.wowhead.com/images/icons/medium/achievement_dungeon_icecrown_frostwinghalls.jpg" /></td><td><a href="http://db.mmo-champion.com/a/4527"><b>The Frostwing Halls (10 player)</b></a><br />Defeat the bosses of The Frostwing Halls in Icecrown Citadel in 10-player mode.</td></tr>
<tr bgcolor=""><td><img src="http://static.wowhead.com/images/icons/medium/achievement_boss_sindragosa.jpg" /></td><td><a href="http://db.mmo-champion.com/a/4580"><b>Sindragosa (10 player)</b></a><br />PH in 10-player mode.</td></tr>

</table>]]>
			</description>
			<comments>http://www.mmo-champion.com/news-2/sindragosa-us-ptr-testing/?action=post</comments>
			<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
			<pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2009 23:14:21 GMT</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.mmo-champion.com/news-2/sindragosa-us-ptr-testing/msg1672271/#msg1672271</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Chill of the Throne, Tanking, and You!]]></title>
			<link>http://www.mmo-champion.com/news-2/chill-of-the-throne-tanking-and-you!/</link>
			<description>
<![CDATA[<b><span style="color: red;">Update</span></b> - Added Ghostcrawler&#39;s posts<br /><br /><font size="3" style="line-height: 1.3em;"><b>Chill of the Throne, Tanking, and You!</b></font><br /><div class="blizzquotewrap"><div class="blizzquoteinner"><span class="corners-top"><span></span></span><div class="blizzquoteheader"><span>Quote from: <b>Daelo (<a href="http://blue.mmo-champion.com/12/20677352541-chill-of-the-throne-tanking-and-you.html" target="_blank" style="color: white;">Source</a>)</span></b></div><div class="blizzquote">For Icecrown Citadel, we are implementing a spell that will affect every enemy creature in the raid. The spell, called Chill of the Throne, will allow creatures to ignore 20% of the dodge chance of their melee targets. So if a raid&#39;s main tank had 30% dodge normally, in Icecrown Citadel they will effectively have 10%.<br /><br />Why are we doing this?<br /><br />The high levels of tank avoidance players have obtained is making the incoming damage a tank DOES take more &quot;spiky&quot; than is healthy for raiding. Ideally, tanks would be receiving a relatively constant stream of damage over time. This allows healers to better plan their healing strategy, broaden their spell options, and simply give more time to react. Tanks could use their cooldowns more reactively. Instead, the current situation is that if we make a hard hitting melee boss and a tank doesn&#39;t avoid two successive swings then the tank could very well be dead in that 1-2 second window. The use of reactive defensive abilities instead becomes a methodically planned affair, healers have to spam their largest heals just in case the huge damage spike happens.<br /><br />We&#39;ve been trying to do a fair amount to mitigate the effect of high tank avoidance on the encounter side of things during this expansion with faster melee swings, additional melee strikes, dual wielding, narrowing the normal variance of melee swing damage, and various other tricks. There&#39;s a limit to what we can do, however. So to give us a bit of breathing room we’ve implemented Chill of the Throne. Going forward past Icecrown Citadel, we have plans to keep tank avoidance from growing so high again.<br /><br />We&#39;ll have this on the PTR soon so players can see the effects inside Icecrown Raid. </div><span class="corners-bottom"><span></span></span></div></div><br />Ghostcrawler also posted about that a few minutes later. <br /><div class="blizzquotewrap"><div class="blizzquoteinner"><span class="corners-top"><span></span></span><div class="blizzquoteheader"><span>Quote from: <b>Ghostcrawler (<a href="http://blue.mmo-champion.com/26/20677632379-icewell-radiance-is-in.html" target="_blank" style="color: white;">Source</a>)</span></b></div><div class="blizzquote">Our original estimations for tank avoidance would have worked fine had we not decided to add extra tiers of gear to reward heroic boss kills halfway through the expansion.<br /><br />The Cataclysm design will keep tank avoidance at more manageable levels. The loss of defense skill counts for a lot right there. We are also considering giving bosses expertise or other ways of baking in Icewell Radiance -- basically the concept that bosses scale with gear rather than just hitting harder and taking more hits. <br /><br /><span style="color: white;"><i>It would still be fine if the itemization team had designed the gear accordingly. In a full 258 setup for warrior tanks, precisely two pieces have anything but a 3 way split of pure avoidance stats on them. There&#39;s 3 different avoidance stats on 3 different diminishing returns, and pumping them all up like that can really make avoidance numbers go way out of whack. Meanwhile, we lose out on things like Expertise, and the preciously rare Hit Rating which is available on *1* piece of 258 tanking gear and end up having to swap gear around to cover those deficiencies. </i></span><br />You are making the common mistake in thinking that our goal for itemization is to give you the best possible gear that we can. Itemizing your character is supposed to be a choice. There will be better pieces and worse pieces. There will be pieces that combine stats your really want with stats you don&#39;t really need. Wearing the best gear for their character (which is not the same as wearing the best gear) is one way players have to demonstrate mastery of the game.<br /><br />This is also why I always preach to take BiS lists with a grain of salt. Merely reaching for the item declared to be BiS by a spreadsheet or system you might not even understand could lead you to making bad gear choices, often of the variety of passing over the good upgrade because it&#39;s not the best possible upgrade.<br /><br /><span style="color: white;"><i>Also, if you&#39;re going to give mobs expertise, can you please make a spell or some kind of method to determine the level of expertise without us having to do parses?</i></span><br />Yes. We would probably just let you see the numbers directly. I consider it a design flaw that players have to experiment to determine thinks like hit and expertise caps. We&#39;re all for experimentation and theorycrafting, but we don&#39;t think it&#39;s fair to require some players to go out and do a lot of work to generate specific numbers that all players feel like they need to know. <br /><br /><span style="color: white;"><i>Putting so much avoidance on gear isn&#39;t a bad idea because other stats are better. It was a bad idea because it causes tank scaling to fail and makes Radiance necessary.</i></span><br />That logic doesn&#39;t really work. It&#39;s like saying instead of nerfing armor pen, we should have just put less and less on higher level gear.<br /><br />If we had avoided avoidance on tank gear, then every piece of tank gear would have hit and expertise (and maybe crit, haste and armor pen). Stamina and armor are static amounts, and if they were not, then those pieces immediately become the only pieces players would pay attention to. <br /><br /><span style="color: white;"><i>If you want ICC damage to be steadier, why don&#39;t you just walk over to the item team and say &quot;Hey, we&#39;d like less avoidance, can you cut out half of the avoidance from the ICC gear and replace it with stamina?&quot; Or if you&#39;re worried people will get too much stamina, make it Frost Resistance and put in so much Frost damage you couldn&#39;t hope to survive long with TotGC gear alone.</i></span><br /><br />We just don&#39;t think that works. If you put very unattractive stats on gear then players just go back the previous tier of gear and complain that we don&#39;t know how to itemize. If you put bonus stamina on the tier 10 gear, then that means the next tier of gear better have bonus stamina as well. If it has avoidance instead of that bonus stamina, tanks just shrug and go back to the tier 10 gear.<br /><br />This is not a tank only problem. Casters won&#39;t upgrade to gear that doesn&#39;t have more spell power on it, because spell power tends to trump everything else for purposes of their dps or healing.<br /><br />We put a little bonus armor on non-armor items (necks, rings, trinkets and the occasional cloak). We don&#39;t put bonus armor on gloves and chests because that gear would be too good.<br /><br />It&#39;s an item level problem. If we added another raid tier to Lich King, we couldn&#39;t just keep avoiding avoidance and avoid it for every tier going forward. We just need a system where you avoid a Naxx boss 30% of the time and an Icecrown boss 30% of the time, the same way the Icecrown bosses have e.g. 30% larger health bars and thus take 30% more damage to kill. Otherwise the stats don&#39;t scale and bad thing happen (in this case the boss having to land so much damage to account for the fact that it misses so often). </div><span class="corners-bottom"><span></span></span></div></div>]]>
			</description>
			<comments>http://www.mmo-champion.com/news-2/chill-of-the-throne-tanking-and-you!/?action=post</comments>
			<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
			<pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2009 19:06:49 GMT</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.mmo-champion.com/news-2/chill-of-the-throne-tanking-and-you!/msg1671053/#msg1671053</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title><![CDATA[EU PTR Testing - Rotface]]></title>
			<link>http://www.mmo-champion.com/news-2/eu-ptr-testing-rotface-122623/</link>
			<description>
<![CDATA[<font size="3" style="line-height: 1.3em;"><b>EU PTR Testing - Rotface</b></font><br />Rotface, one of the 3 bosses of the Plague wing of Icecrown Citadel will be available for testing on EU PTRs tonight, starting 18:30 CET. <br /><br /><div align="center"><a href="http://static.mmo-champion.com/mmoc/images/news/2009/october/rotface.jpg" target="_blank"><img src="http://static.mmo-champion.com/mmoc/images/news/2009/october/rotface_small2.jpg" alt="" border="0" /></a></div><br /><div align="center"><font size="3" style="line-height: 1.3em;"><b>Streams</b></font></div><br /><div align="center">No more streams for today!</div><br /><div align="center"><font size="3" style="line-height: 1.3em;"><b>Abilities</b></font></div><br /><table bgcolor="#FFFFFF" width="700px" border="0" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="1" style="border-left: 1px solid #96BC27; border-right: 1px solid #96BC27; border-top: 1px solid #96BC27; margin:auto;">
			<tr><td style="padding-left: 5px"><b>Rotface</b></td></tr>
			</table>
			<table bgcolor="#FFFFFF" width="700px" class="sortable" border="0" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="1" style="border: 1px solid #96BC27; margin:auto;">
			<tr bgcolor="#96BC27">
			<td width="30">&nbsp;</td>
			<td width="150"><b>Spell</b></td>
			<td width="520"><b>Description</b></td>
			</tr>
			</table>
			<table bgcolor="#FFFFFF" width="700px" class="sortable" border="0" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="1" style="border: 1px solid #96BC27; margin:auto;">
			<tr bgcolor="">
				<td class="tableData"><a target="_blank" href="http://db.mmo-champion.com/s/69508"><img border="0" width="30" height="30" src="http://static.wowhead.com/images/icons/medium/spell_fire_felcano.jpg"></a></td>
				<td class="tableData"><a target="_blank" href="http://db.mmo-champion.com/s/69508"><b>Slime Spray</b></a><br></td>
				<td class="tableData"><b>Raining Green Ooze. Deals 5363 to 5637 Nature to enemies in cone.</b> 1.5 sec cast / Channeled</td>
			</tr>
			<tr bgcolor="#e0e0e0">
				<td class="tableData"><a target="_blank" href="http://db.mmo-champion.com/s/71224"><img border="0" width="30" height="30" src="http://static.wowhead.com/images/icons/medium/ability_creature_disease_02.jpg"></a></td>
				<td class="tableData"><a target="_blank" href="http://db.mmo-champion.com/s/71224/"><b>Mutated Infection</b></a><br></td>

				<td class="tableData"><b>The Mutated Infection inflicts 3900 to 4100 damage every 1 sec and reduces healing receieved by 50% for 12 sec. &nbsp;After the Infection is removed a small ooze is created at the target's location.</b> Instant</td>
			</tr>
			<tr bgcolor="">
				<td class="tableData"><a target="_blank" href="http://db.mmo-champion.com/s/71213"><img border="0" width="30" height="30" src="http://static.wowhead.com/images/icons/medium/spell_shadow_fumble.jpg"></a></td>
				<td class="tableData"><a target="_blank" href="http://db.mmo-champion.com/s/71213/"><b>Slime Spray</b></a><br></td>

				<td class="tableData"><b>Deals 6338 to 6662 Nature damage to enemies in a cone infront of the enemy.</b> Instant</td>
			</tr>
			</table>
			<table bgcolor="#FFFFFF" width="700px" class="sortable" border="0" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="1" style="border-left: 1px solid #96BC27; border-right: 1px solid #96BC27; margin:auto;">
			<tr><td style="padding-left: 5px"><p><b>Sticky Ooze</b> (Spawned each time Mutated Infection is debuffed / expired)</b></p></td></tr>
			</table>
			<table bgcolor="#FFFFFF" width="700px" class="sortable" border="0" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="1" style="border: 1px solid #96BC27; margin:auto;">
			<tr bgcolor="#e0e0e0">
				<td class="tableData"><a target="_blank" href="http://db.mmo-champion.com/s/69774"><img border="0" width="30" height="30" src="http://static.wowhead.com/images/icons/medium/spell_shadow_plaguecloud.jpg"></a></td>
				<td class="tableData"><a target="_blank" href="http://db.mmo-champion.com/s/69774/"><b>Sticky Ooze</b></a><br></td>
				<td class="tableData"><b>The Ooze sprays a puddle of Green Goo near the target. The Green Goo inflicts 2925 to 3075 damage every 1 sec and decreases move speed by 50%.</b> 1 sec cast</td>
			</tr>

			</table>
			<table bgcolor="#FFFFFF" width="700px" class="sortable" border="0" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="1" style="border-left: 1px solid #96BC27; border-right: 1px solid #96BC27; margin:auto;">
			<tr><td style="padding-left: 5px"><p><b>Big Ooze</b> (Spawns when 2 Sticky Ooze merge, a Sticky Ooze can merge with the Big Ooze and adds a stack of Unstable Ooze. Two Big Oozes can merge and combine their stacks. When the Ooze reaches 5 stacks it will explode.)</b></p></td></tr>
			</table>
			<table bgcolor="#FFFFFF" width="700px" class="sortable" border="0" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="1" style="border: 1px solid #96BC27; margin:auto;">
			<tr bgcolor="">
				<td class="tableData"><a target="_blank" href="http://db.mmo-champion.com/s/69558"><img border="0" width="30" height="30" src="http://static.wowhead.com/images/icons/medium/spell_shadow_unstableaffliction_2.jpg"></a></td>
				<td class="tableData"><a target="_blank" href="http://db.mmo-champion.com/s/69558/"><b>Unstable Ooze</b></a><br></td>
				<td class="tableData"><b>Increases damage dealt by 20%.</b> Instant</td>
			</tr>
			<tr bgcolor="#e0e0e0">
				<td class="tableData"><a target="_blank" href="http://db.mmo-champion.com/s/69774"><img border="0" width="30" height="30" src="http://static.wowhead.com/images/icons/medium/spell_shadow_plaguecloud.jpg"></a></td>
				<td class="tableData"><a target="_blank" href="http://db.mmo-champion.com/s/69774/"><b>Sticky Ooze</b></a><br></td>
				<td class="tableData"><b>The Ooze sprays a puddle of Green Goo near the target. The Green Goo inflicts 2925 to 3075 damage every 1 sec and decreases move speed by 50%.</b> &nbsp;1 sec cast</td>
			</tr>
			<tr bgcolor="">
				<td class="tableData"><a target="_blank" href="http://db.mmo-champion.com/s/69839"><img border="0" width="30" height="30" src="http://static.wowhead.com/images/icons/medium/ability_creature_poison_06.jpg"></a></td>
				<td class="tableData"><a target="_blank" href="http://db.mmo-champion.com/s/69839/"><b>Unstable Ooze Explosion</b></a><br></td>
				<td class="tableData"><b>Inflicts 9750 to 10250 damage to enemies within 6 yards.</b> 4 sec cast</td>
			</tr>
			<tr bgcolor="#e0e0e0">
				<td class="tableData"><a target="_blank" href="http://db.mmo-champion.com/s/71212"><img border="0" width="30" height="30" src="http://static.wowhead.com/images/icons/medium/inv_misc_slime_01.jpg"></a></td>
				<td class="tableData"><a target="_blank" href="http://db.mmo-champion.com/s/71212/"><b>Radiating Ooze</b></a><br></td>
				<td class="tableData"><b>Inflicts 4388 to 4612 damage to enemies within 10 yards.</b> Instant</td>
			</tr>

			</table><br /><div align="center"><font size="3" style="line-height: 1.3em;"><b>Achievements</b></font></div><br /><table bgcolor="#FFFFFF" border="0" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="1" style="border: 1px solid #96BC27; margin:auto;">
			<tr bgcolor="#96BC27">
			<td class="tableHeader" width="45"></td>
			<td class="tableHeader" width="655"><b>Description</b></td>
			</tr>
<tr bgcolor=""><td><img src="http://static.wowhead.com/images/icons/medium/spell_nature_acid_01.jpg" /></td><td><a href="http://db.mmo-champion.com/a/4538"><b>Dances with Oozes (10 player)</b></a><br />Defeat Rotface without exploding any oozes in 10-player mode.</td></tr>
<tr bgcolor=""><td><img src="http://static.wowhead.com/images/icons/medium/achievement_boss_tribunalofages.jpg" /></td><td><a href="http://db.mmo-champion.com/a/4528"><b>The Plagueworks (10 player)</b></a><br />Defeat the bosses of The Plagueworks in Icecrown Citadel in 10-player mode.</td></tr>

</table>]]>
			</description>
			<comments>http://www.mmo-champion.com/news-2/eu-ptr-testing-rotface-122623/?action=post</comments>
			<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
			<pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2009 17:36:09 GMT</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.mmo-champion.com/news-2/eu-ptr-testing-rotface-122623/msg1670672/#msg1670672</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Queen Lana'thel, Icecrown Citadel, Blue posts]]></title>
			<link>http://www.mmo-champion.com/news-2/queen-lana'thel-icecrown-citadel-blue-posts/</link>
			<description>
<![CDATA[<font size="3" style="line-height: 1.3em;"><b>Queen Lana&#39;thel Model</b></font><br />The BloodQueen model added in the latest PTR build was quite popular, I made a short video to let you enjoy the 360° view. <br /><br /><center><object width="640" height="405"><param name="movie" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/D0WF8a3U-9c"><b>Icecrown Citadel Changes in latest build</b></font><br />The latest PTR build changed Icecrown Citadel, but this time we&#39;re talking about the outdoor appearance of the citadel. It now looks MUCH taller and a new structure has been added at the top ... If you remember the early screenshots of the citadel I posted you might recognize the location.<br /><br /><div align="center"><a href="http://static.mmo-champion.com/mmoc/images/news/2009/october/citadel1.jpg" target="_blank"><img src="http://static.mmo-champion.com/mmoc/images/news/2009/october/citadel1_small.jpg" alt="" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://static.mmo-champion.com/mmoc/images/news/2009/october/citadel2.jpg" target="_blank"><img src="http://static.mmo-champion.com/mmoc/images/news/2009/october/citadel2_small.jpg" alt="" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://static.mmo-champion.com/mmoc/images/news/2009/october/citadel3.jpg" target="_blank"><img src="http://static.mmo-champion.com/mmoc/images/news/2009/october/citadel3_small.jpg" alt="" border="0" /></a></div><br /><font size="3" style="line-height: 1.3em;"><b>New Dungeon System</b></font><br /><div class="blizzquotewrap"><div class="blizzquoteinner"><span class="corners-top"><span></span></span><div class="blizzquoteheader"><span>Quote from: <b>Blizzard (<a href="http://www.worldofwarcraft.com/info/underdev/3p3/newdungeonsystem.xml" target="_blank" style="color: white;">Source</a>)</span></b></div><div class="blizzquote">In the upcoming content patch there are many new additions and improvements. Perhaps one of the largest changes is the introduction of the new dungeon system. This new system will be available for all dungeons. A “Dungeons” button will replace the Looking For Group feature currently available in-game, and provides additional benefits to those who use it.<br /><br /><span style="color: white;"><b>System Highlights:</b></span><br /><ul style="margin-top: 0; margin-bottom: 0;"><li>Join as a Group or Solo</li><li>Cross-Realm Instances/Grouping</li><li>Instance Teleporting</li><li>Smarter Group Matching</li><li>Daily Random Dungeons</li><li>Repeat Random Dungeons</li><li>Choose Multiple Dungeons</li><li>Vote Kick system</li><li>Lovin’ the PUG Bonuses</li><li>Looking For Raid</li><li>Need Before Greed Updated</li><li>Group Disenchanting</li></ul><br /><span style="color: white;"><b>Join as a Group or Solo</b></span><br />Much like the current Looking For Group system, players will be able to join the dungeon system and choose the role they would like to fill within groups: Healing, DPS, or Tank. In addition, once roles have been identified, they will be applied to all dungeons chosen. Players will now be able to choose multiple dungeons and will no longer be limited to three. The system has also improved group creation and matchmaking capabilities and will create more balanced groups when assessing the selected roles of players.<br /><br />The LFG channel has been disconnected from the dungeon tool and can be used by anyone in a major city, much like the trade channel currently available.<br /><br /><span style="color: white;"><b>Cross Realm Instances</b></span><br />When joining the dungeon system as a solo player or with a partial group, additional random players can be found within the same Battlegroup via cross-realm instancing.<br /><br />While the new system offers the ability to group with player from other realms within your Battlegroup, you won’t be able to use this to manually invite specific players to groups.<br /><br /><span style="color: white;"><b>Instance Teleporting</b></span><br />When you use the dungeon tool to find a dungeon, you’ll get ported to the inside of the dungeon, much like the current Battleground system. When you leave the instance, you will be returned to your previous location. If you need to leave temporarily, such as for repairs or to purchase reagents, you can teleport back to the dungeon again. This feature can be used both by groups looking for other players and by premade groups of five who use the dungeon tool.<br /><br /><span style="color: white;"><b>Smarter Group Matching</b></span><br />The new system will now work to match at least one experienced player for the assigned dungeon with less experienced players in the group. It will more carefully match class types, and will more consistently match players of equal levels for the dungeon chosen. The interface will also allow players to see how many players are looking for groups as well as the average wait time of groups that the tool has formed.<br /><br /><span style="color: white;"><b>Daily Random Dungeons</b></span><br />Players or groups can choose specific dungeons or they can instead take their chances with a random Heroic or random normal dungeon. Picking randomly conveys some additional benefits. If you defeat the final boss in a dungeon, you receive 2 Emblems of Frost for Heroic dungeons and 2 Emblems of Triumph for normal dungeons. In addition, after players have received 2 Emblems of Frost for the first Heroic dungeon they do in a day, they will earn 2 Emblems of Triumph for each additional random Heroic dungeons in that day. These random rewards replace the current daily dungeon and daily Heroic dungeon quests. The current NPCs who offer those quests will offer weekly repeatable raid quests instead. You can also earn level-appropriate rewards for running random pre-Wrath of the Lich King dungeons while you are leveling up.<br /><br /><span style="color: white;"><b>Lovin’ the PUG</b></span><br />Players who take part in groups with one or more members who have been matched with them randomly from within the dungeon system will receive extra rewards, including the coveted Perky Pug non-combat pet. The more random players you group with, the faster you could get your new pet!<br /><br /><span style="color: white;"><b>Vote Kick</b></span><br />Players who use the system to find additional random members for their party will be afforded a couple of extra conveniences to help them perform well. The loot option is fixed to the updated Need Before Greed option (and unalterable by any member) and players can vote to remove another party member from the group. It will take four votes in order to remove someone, however, so consider this newfound power carefully.<br /><br /><span style="color: white;"><b>Looking for Raid</b></span><br />There will be a new option available to players that can be accessed via the raid information screen in the interface or by typing /lfr. Players will also be able to take part in raid-specific weekly quests and will be able to browse the system manually for any other players looking for a raid dungeon group.<br /><br /><span style="color: white;"><b>Need Before Greed Updated</b></span><br />Need Before Greed will now recognize gear appropriate for a class in three ways: the class must be able to equip the item, pure melee will be unable to roll on spellpower items, and classes are limited to their dominant armor type (for example, plate for paladins). All items will still be available via greed rolls should no member be able to use the item as well as the new disenchant option will be available for all parties.<br /><br /><span style="color: white;"><b>Group Disenchanting</b></span><br />Players in a group with an enchanter will now have the option to automatically disenchant any items that are not claimed by a player from within the loot window. Players will have this option available to them in both premade groups and in randomly matched groups. This option is available in any loot system, even if players don’t use the new dungeon tool.</div><span class="corners-bottom"><span></span></span></div></div><br /><div align="center"><a href="http://static.mmo-champion.com/mmoc/images/news/2009/october/nds1.jpg" target="_blank"><img src="http://static.mmo-champion.com/mmoc/images/news/2009/october/nds1_small.jpg" alt="" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://static.mmo-champion.com/mmoc/images/news/2009/october/nds2.jpg" target="_blank"><img src="http://static.mmo-champion.com/mmoc/images/news/2009/october/nds2_small.jpg" alt="" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://static.mmo-champion.com/mmoc/images/news/2009/october/nds3.jpg" target="_blank"><img src="http://static.mmo-champion.com/mmoc/images/news/2009/october/nds3_small.jpg" alt="" border="0" /></a></div><br /><font size="3" style="line-height: 1.3em;"><b>Disenchanting in Dungeons in Patch 3.3</b></font><br /><div class="blizzquotewrap"><div class="blizzquoteinner"><span class="corners-top"><span></span></span><div class="blizzquoteheader"><span>Quote from: <b>Bornakk (<a href="http://blue.mmo-champion.com/15/20677331778-disenchanting-in-dungeons-in-patch-33.html" target="_blank" style="color: white;">Source</a>)</span></b></div><div class="blizzquote">As we mentioned in the recent post explaining the new Dungeon System, disenchanting will work a little differently in all 5 player and raid dungeons when patch 3.3 is released. We have seen a consistent pattern where players eventually need very few items from dungeons and they result to disenchanting as much of the loot as possible since those materials that can be obtained continue to have a lot of worth.<br /><br />When the new Dungeon System is launched, the default user interface will give players the option to automatically disenchant items that they obtain in 5 player and raid dungeons. This option will avoid the hassle of having items picked up by an enchanter first to redistributed later and overall will make the process much smoother.<br /><br />Also, with the inclusion of cross-realm-instancing in the dungeon system, there will be restrictions on trading items similar to the restrictions that are currently active in Battlegrounds. If the Dungeon System is used to complete a group for a dungeon then non-temporary items will not be able to be traded in the instance. This makes it so items like enchanting materials will not be able to be traded in the dungeon and using the new user interface option will be the only way to distribute disenchants. There will be some exceptions to this restriction though as Bind-on-Pickup items will continue to be trade-able to those present for the kill for a short duration and completely pre-formed groups that don’t use the Dungeon System to form the group will still allow trades.<br /><br />To maintain the importance of the profession itself, the disenchanting UI option will only be available for groups that have a character with the necessary level of Enchanting to disenchant the items that are obtained.<br /><br />We are very excited about the upcoming improvements in the new Dungeon Sys...</div><span class="corners-bottom"><span></span></span></div></div>]]>
			</description>
			<comments>http://www.mmo-champion.com/news-2/queen-lana'thel-icecrown-citadel-blue-posts/?action=post</comments>
			<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
			<pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2009 07:49:19 GMT</pubDate>
			<guid>http://www.mmo-champion.com/news-2/queen-lana'thel-icecrown-citadel-blue-posts/msg1668619/#msg1668619</guid>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>